Let you opponents tremble with fear
日本語字幕仕上げ：光川  光荣字幕组（www.koeigame.cn）
I’ll stop him!
止めてやる！
Alright, he fell for it.
よし　釣れた
That's disappointing, Miku...I’ve already warned you.
哀れなミック
あんなに忠告したのに
Shiro!
シロさん
Hit it towards me.
俺のところで流れ変えますよ
I can get it!
What? I didn’t touch him!
俺 今 触ってないス！
イ　イエロ？
Yellow?
Was there even contact?
触ってましたか？
Who knows.
わかんない
But the opponent baited him.
でも　誘われたのは確かだ
He's a sly one...
うまいな…　あいつ
Damn, we conceded.
チッ　やられた
United we stand,Fly a flag 風を受け止めて
United we stand, Fly a flag!
kaze o uketomete
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand,Fly a flag たなびけ勝利のflag
United we stand, Fly a flag!
tanabike shouri no flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けていて
haruka na gooru o shinjite
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
for the right
For the right! Hold on tight!
hold on tight
my story…
My story...
forever
Forever...
The current score is 1-1.
前半終わって１対１
ETU’s pulling out all the stops, aren’t they?
ＥＴＵも頑張ってはいますけどねぇ
Still, I think Tokyo Victory will dominate from here on out.
後半は　東京ヴィクトリの　一方的な展開になるんじゃないです
The difference in their strengths is too wide.
やっぱり圧倒的に実力の差が
That reporter’s pissing me off.
あの記者　許すまじ
But still, I wonder whether they'll be alright...
でも…　大丈夫かな
後半
す…　すみませんでした
I-I’m sorry!
お…　俺のファウルで…
It was my foul that...
It's not your fault, so don’t worry about it.
済んだ事は　気にしたってしかたないだろ
That’s right, moron!
そうだ　バカ野郎！
That bastard Mochida plays dirty!
持田って野郎は汚ねえんだよ
俺も去年は　だまされまくってカード　もらいまくったからな
He once tricked the referee into giving me a card too...
Don't boast about it.
自慢げに言うなよ
Still, if we don’t come up with a plan for the second half, we’re not going to win the midfield.
でも　後半　何とかしねえと
中盤　支配されっぱなしっスよ
Exactly.
そのとおり
Because of that, it's time for a tactical change: Miyano in, Ishigami out.
だから手を打つ
宮野インで　石神アウト
In the second half, we'll switch formation from 4-5-1 to 3-6-1.
前半の４-５-１から　後半は３-６-１
The attacking Miyano will be used to seize the midfield.
攻撃激な宮野を　右サイドに入れて中盤を取り返す
Gino and Akasaki will play up front.
ジーノと赤崎は　２人でトップ下
Do get along.
仲よくやれよ
Take care of me, Zaki.
楽させてね　ザッキ
I'm exhausted from taking on two defenders just now.
２人も相手して疲れちゃったからさ
Go forward, Miyano.
宮野もガンガン行けよ
Don’t worry about tracking back.
後ろなんか気にすんな
あ　ウス！
Yes!
Whether or not the opponents exploit the space left behind by Miyano will depend on the two of you.
宮野の裏スペースここを取られるかどうかは
ボランチ２人の頑張りしだい
So go all out, you guys!
だからお前ら　頑張れ
For the second half, the opponents will be full of themselves after that equalizer.
後半　向こうは同点になって調子に乗ってくる
Don’t panic even if they're dominating.
ヤツらのペースになっても慌てんな
So long as that look on your faces don’t die,
お前らの顔は死んでねえ
We have a chance to win this!
ここぞのチャンスで一気に決める
ヴィクトリなんて　ダセエ名前の連中
Beat those guys with a shitty name like “Victory”.
Straight down to the ground!
お前らで　ぶっつぶしてこい！
よし！　やってやらあ！
All right, let’s roll guys! Let's destroy Victory!
行くぞ　オラァ　ぶっつぶす！
At moments like these, Kuroda’s really useful.
こういう時　クロは単純で助かる
Tsubaki.
椿
If you falter now, your efforts in the first half will count for nothing.
ここで迷っちまったら
前半のお前は意味ねえぞ
Don't be afraid to commit fouls.
ファウルなんかにビビんじゃねえ
Conversely, make the crowd tremble with fear.
逆に　ここの連中　ビビらせてこい
ウ…　ウス
Yes.
So they sacrificed a defender for a midfielder, eh?
ディフェンダーを１人下げてミッドフィルダーを足してきたか
Tatsumi...
達海監督
Are you planning a midfield battle?
ウチと中盤でやり合おうとでも？
Sorry though. We, Tokyo Victory, will never lose in a direct confrontation against small teams.
…悪いが 東京ヴィクトリは
そんな真っ向勝負でやられる相手ではないよ
So you’re still coming after me, even after you got a card, eh?
カードもらってんのに果敢に来るねぇ
Charge!
行け
All right! Go for it!
よし　攻めろ！
攻撃に何人かけんだよ…
Just what is the offense thinking?
Attack!
仕掛けろ！！
Pass it!
来い！
So close!
惜しい！
The left side’s unguarded! Attack!
左サイド
空いてるぞ
あ　宮野の裏を狙われた
That's space left behind by Miyano!
A chance!
チャンス！
行け
Charge!
ナイスカバー
Nice cover!
As expected of Murakoshi. He's good.
さすが村越ですね　読みがいい
Amazing.
すげえ
That was such a quick wing play.
いきなりサイドの攻防戦だ
すごいな村越さん
Murakoshi’s amazing.
Now, my turn...
…俺も！
Miyano, just keep on charging!
宮野　その調子でどんどん行け！
赤崎　フォローに走れよ！
Akasaki, remember to assist him!
Zaki!
ザキさん！
Tamba, it's yours!
タンさん　合わせろ！
いい形　作れてる
Nice link-up play.
速攻　気を付けろ！
Be careful!
左サイドもう一人　フォロー行け！
Get another man down the left wing!
Hey, over here!
ヘイヘイ　こっち！
Mochida!
モチさん
ナイスカット　椿！
Nice one, Tsubaki!
Bastard...
ヤロ……
We're fending them off!
押してんのは俺たちだ！
Dad...
父ちゃん
俺…今　久しぶりにＥＴＵのサッカー
I've...never found ETU's play...
面白いと思った
...to be that interesting.
Only fifteen minutes left in the second half.
後半残り１５分…
Tatsumi…
達海のヤツ交代カード３枚とも使ってきたか
He’s going to use up all three substitutes that early?
Well, Sera and Tamba have been running around throughout the match.
確かに
世良と丹波は序盤から走り回っていたが…
Is that okay, Tatsumi? The match is now out of your control.
いいのか？　達海
この試合　監督として動ける事はもう何もないんだぞ
いいの　いいの
It’ll be okay.
Now to see how things will go.
あとは見てようぜ
か…　監督
M-Manager?!
Didn’t I say before the match?
それに　試合前に言ったじゃん
俺の仕事は引き分けまでだって
My goal is to draw at best.
But…
あ　しかし…
精神論は嫌いだけどね
I hate speculating on psychology...
Now that we're late into the game, the deciding factor now will be their willpower.
この時間帯に入ったら あとは気力がものを言うよ
From what I saw at the camp, they all wanted to win badly.
キャンプの　あいつらを見て
勝ちたがっているのは　わかった
What matters now is whether they will be able to play better than the champions.
問題は　それがチャンピオンチームに勝るものなのか
In order to transform this team,
チームが強くなる上で一番大切な部分
The key here...
...is to truly understand their capabilities.
そいつを見極めるんだ
It's been awhile since we started the second half.
後半からのサイド攻撃で
向こうも走らされて疲れているはず
The opponents should be tiring out.
As substitutes, we should be running at them to create chances.
新しく入った俺たちが走って
チャンス作んねえと
Akasaki!
赤崎！
It's our turn to seize the initiative. Just you wait and see!
抜いてやる！
そして俺もスタメンの座を！
What?!
なにっ？
The international, Shironishi!
代表　城西！
He's still able to run?
まだ走れんのかよ　コイツ！
So we're attacking once again...
またサイドから攻めるか？
That lazy bastard.
あの野郎
Gino has the cheek to stroll through the game?
ジーノのヤツあからさまにサボりやがって
But I was constantly double-teamed during the first half.
前半２人も相手にしたんだよ
That's quite enough for the day.
今日　十分働いたでしょ
Tsubaki! Chase him down!
椿　止めろ！
This is it!
レオナルド　決めてよ！
Hey! That was a close one!
おいおい　あぶねえよ
Darn, why does that Brazilian have to flop at the most crucial of times?
あ~あ　何でいつもこの時期のブラジル人って　調整不足なのかねぇ
It seems like I will have to score myself.
こりゃ　自分で点取りに行くしかないな
お前の実力だ　椿
That is your strength, Tsubaki.
Do your best.
そのまま行けー
No matter times you fail...
何度でもしくじれー
そのかわり
All you need is that one chance to dazzle the crowd and frighten your opponents.
１回のプレーで観客を酔わせろー
どぎも敵の度肝を抜けー
お前ん中の…ジャイアントキリングを起こせー
Bring out the spirit of Giant Killing in you.
GIANT KILLING
させるもんか
I won't let you have your way!
Ten minutes left in the second half...
後半も残り１０分
A draw should be a fairly good result against such an opponent.
接戦で王者相手に引き分けってのは
悪くないんじゃないか
How could you be satisfied with just a draw?
引き分けで喜んで　どうする？
Anyway, the lads are doing a good job.
とはいえ
選手は頑張っているが
Though we don't seem to have control of the match...can we score another goal?
なかなか　うちのペースにならんなぁ
もう１点　取れるか…
Well, I hope so but...
取ってほしいところですが…
但无论是球权的控制
The control of the ball...
The opponent's teamwork...
代表選手の必死さ
The determination of the internationals...
As well as the deafening cheers of their supporters...
そして　それを後押しするこの大声援
To win with these factors against us is certainly not an easy task...
のまれるなと言うほうが
難しいのかもしれない
パス回しが　速い！
Their passes are quick!
椿が抜かれた！
They went past Tsubaki!
Damn it!
クソー！
スギはレオナルドのチェック！
Sugi, mark Leornado! Kuroda, prevent Mochida from shooting!
クロは持田のシュートコースを！
ぬ　抜いてきた！
He's through!
I'll stop him!
俺が止めるんだ
俺が！
I will...
ループ！
短いか?
Was it too tame?
ドリ！　追いつける！
Dori, save it!
頑張りがアダになったねぇ
Your hard work has gone to waste.
サンキュ　椿君
Thank you, Tsubaki!
２点とも…　俺のせいで…
We conceded...and it's all my fault.
立て　椿
Get up, Tsubaki. Today's mistakes weren't your fault.
今のは責められるミスじゃない
That look on his face...this match's over for Tsubaki.
あの様子じゃ椿は
この試合　もう無理か
ここまで　しのいできたのに
Sigh, and we were holding them up for so long...
あ…何してるんです？　監督
What are you doing, manager?
人間観察
Observing the players.
はい？
Huh?
残り時間５分
Only five minutes left...
強豪相手に互角の勝負をしてきて
We had played on level terms with the champs but eventually handed them the lead...
もうちょいってとこで逆転された
そんな時どんなツラしてやがんのか
In such a situation, what state of mind will the players have?
Have they cracked?
もう駄目って顔なのか
まだやれるって顔なのか
Or otherwise.
選手の本性が顔に出る
We can clearly see each player's personality from this.
ここで下を向いているようなヤツには
Those who think that all is lost now...
フットボールの神様はほほ笑まねえ
The footballing gods won't be smiling upon them.
椿！下向くんじゃねえ！
Tsubaki!
Don't get your head down!
つけ込まれるぞ
Or you'll be taken advantage of!
ウス！
Yes...
クソ…
Damn it.
椿の所を狙われたら　ひとたまりもねえ
We'll be in trouble if Tsubaki is targeted.
かといって
That said though, I'll be leaving a hole if I were to assist him.
俺がカバーに行ったらこっちが空いちまう
赤崎に下がってもらうか…
Should Akasaki track back?
しかし　それでは攻撃の数が…
But that will reduce the number of people in attack.
チームのバランス　戦術
The team's balance and tactics shouldn't be in your area of responsibility.
そんなもんまでお前がしょい込む必要はねえ
だから　キャプテン外すんだよ
That's why I stripped you of your captaincy.
Stop wasting time!
引いてんじゃねえよ！
ふざけんな　コラ！
What are you guys doing?
こんなもん勝つための常識だっつうの？
That's the natural thing to do when you're leading.
チームのために　サッカーをやってきたつもりだった
I've always been playing for the sake of the team.
キャプテンという立場を　自分の逃げ道にしていなかったか？
The captain's armband served as a constant reminder of that to me.
キャプテンマークを奪われた俺はどうだ
What should I do now that I have lost it?
How do you see me as player?
お前らの目に
選手としての俺はどう映っている？
There's space behind them!
裏のスペース
狙えるぞ！
まずい！カウンターか
Crap, a counter-attack!
From here on, seek something in yourself that will help you to succeed.
それでも勝てる自分の武器を
これからお前は死ぬ気で探せぇ
Don't let him pass, Murakoshi!
行かせんな！　村越！
何ができる？
What should I do?
今の俺に…
The present me...
一体　何が?
What can I do?!
Great defending! As expected of Murakoshi!
よく止めた！
さすが村越さん！
それでこそ　ミスターＥＴＵ！
That's our Mr ETU!
Murakoshi's not gonna lose out!
村越の顔はまだ　あきらめてませんよ
This is not the time to think about losing!
負けらんねえとか考えてんじゃねえぞ
You won't win like this, Murakoshi!
それじゃ勝てねえんだ村越！
持ってけ　村越！
Go on, Murakoshi!
１０番　オッケ
I'll take on No.10!
A one-two pass!
ワンツー　通った！
Come on, Murakoshi!
また村越だ！
マーク確認！
Position yourselves!
どこに出してくる？
Where will it come from?
村越　打て！
Shoot, Murakoshi!
村越！　村越！村越！　村越！
双冠王者VS达海 持田梅开二度 仍不分胜负
New look ETU VS 2-time champions
Mochida scores two!
Draw!
監督
Manager...
Sorry for calling you out!
おう　悪いね　わざわざ
勘弁してくださいよ
Give me a break. Calling me out in a place like this.
こんな所で
いいじゃんかよ近所なんだし
What's so bad about it? It's near too.
いいよなぁ　ここ
This is a nice amusement park.
地元って感じがしてさぁ
It makes you feel like being at home.
不思議だよ
Amazing, isn't it?
同じように人が暮らしていて
Although they're the same rides like the ones in the city, they're all different in style and color.
町によって　何でこうも色が違うんだろう
Just like how it is with clubs and teams.
クラブチームも　そうさぁ
それぞれの色ってもんがある
They each have their own colors.
ＥＴＵの色はさあ
While ETU's color-
What do you know about them...as someone who once abandoned the team?
何が地元だ！　町の色だ！
チームを見捨てて　ぶんざい出て行った分際で
いいんすか？
Are you done?
善戦ったって引き分けですよ
It's only a draw.
向こうは本調子じゃなかったし
And the opponents weren't even playing seriously.
こっちは課題がありありと出た
Our problems were exposed one after another.
With that attitude of yours,
あんたが　そんな調子じゃ
次やる時は　ボコボコにされる
We'll get a proper beating the next time round!
おいおい　どこまで半端なんだよ
How long more are you going to be deluded, Mr ETU?
ミスターＥＴＵ
You slow-moving lump of meat.
デケエ図体して　煮えきらねえヤツだ
何いつまでも同じような事言ってやがんだ
How many times am I going to say it?
お前みてえなキャプテンは　いらねえ
I don't need a captain like that!
まだわかんねえのか
Don't you understand?
テメエ！
You bastard...
ま　あのゴールだけはよかった
You did take that shot and scored though...
But you were charging through blindly after that, right?
後先考えずに突っ走った結果じゃねえの？
I want you to etch that memory deeply into your mind.
あの光景を頭に刻んどけ
村越！　村越！村越！　村越！
The cheers of hundreds of our fans...
The childish and thrilled expressions on your teammates...
ガキみたいに駆け寄ってくるチームメートの顔
Your meaning to the team all this while...all of it were summed up in that single moment.
お前を長い間見てきた連中の答えが
あの瞬間に詰まっていた
The team's color...
このチームの色
It's you, Murakoshi.
そいつはお前だ！村越！
前だけ向いてろ！
Keep looking forward!
The condition for this is...
条件はピッチの上じゃ絶対服従
Abiding to my absolute command, fully understanding my actions and relaying them to others.
俺の考えを完全に理解し
選手に徹底させろ
気づいた事は　すべて報告
Report everything you notice to me.
仲間の目なんか気にするな
Ignore what others think of you.
その上で
And above all else, continue developing as a player.
プレーヤーとしてあがき続けろー
I will not hold back if you break any of these conditions.
抜かったら容赦しない
あとね
One more thing,
俺を殺したいと思っても
Even if you are going to kill me, do it after I get sacked.
解任されてからにするように
じゃ　解任されねえように気を付けることっスね
Then you really have to be careful not to get the boot.
You've got find the way to believe
carry on and carry on
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say "never look back"
I'll say “never look back”
追い風を待って
oikaze o matte
Wait for the tailwind
そうchanceをのがすなら
sou chance o nogasunara
And if you missed the chance
自分が風になれ no fears no tears
jibun ga kaze ni nare
Become the wind yourself
no tears,Yes Let it go！
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
限界追い越せ
genkai oikose yuke
Surpass your limits and go!
行け キツイほど
kitsui hodo heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
heart in red
Go on！(Stay cool！）
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
Go on！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
あすは見えない だから
asu wa mienai dakara
Because we can't see into the future
It's time to go
It's time to go yamerarenai
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
やめられない
Get tough!
Get tough！Get tough！ Get tough！
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
共に乗り越えて 行け
tomo ni norikoete yuke
Let's get through it together
見えるか It's daybreak there
mieruka It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
Go on！(Stay cool！) Go on！(We'll go！)
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
We'll go!
予測できないだから
yosoku dekinai dakara
The future is unpredictable
It's time to go
It's time to go tomerarenai
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
止められない
Mixing it up?
Get yourself prepared, quick!
We're heading off!
The next person here is...
No matter how outstanding the manager and his players are...
Who are you?
You have the luck!